<resources>
    <!--  Splash Screen  -->
    <string name="app_name">Flora and Fauna</string>
    <string name="app_greeting">Welcome at flora and fauna Application</string>
    <string name="load_text">wait for a while</string>
    <string name="text_right">© | All rights are Reserved | 2022</string>

    <!--  Dashboard  -->
    <string name="dashboard_greeting">Choose to Explore Flora and Fauna</string>
    <string name="dashboardFloraBtn">Explore Flora In Uttarakhand</string>
    <string name="dashboardFaunaBtn">Explore Fauna in Uttarakhand</string>
    <string name="dashboardRight">Dashboard | Flora And Fauna</string>

    <!--  Flora Dashboard  -->
    <string name="floraIntro">Traditionally, the mountains in the lower regions of Uttarakhand were covered with moist deciduous forest. Between elevations of 1,500 to 3,000m, the major natural vegetation entails of Pine, Oak, Rhododendron, Walnut and Larch. Below the snow line, the vegetation consists of forests of Spruce, Fir, Cypress, Juniper and Birch, while above the snow line (in the higher altitude of the State) is Alpine vegetation which includes Mosses, Lichen and a diversity of wildflowers such as Blue Poppies and Edelweiss.</string>
    <string name="nameBF">Brahma Kamal</string>
    <string name="nameRF">Rhododendron Burans (Buransh)</string>
    <string name="namePF">Pine Tree</string>
    <string name="nameBPF">Blue Poppy</string>
    <string name="nameDesBF">Saussurea Obvallata</string>
    <string name="nameDesRF">Rhododendron Arboreum Sm</string>
    <string name="nameDesPF">Pinus roxburghii</string>
    <string name="nameDesBPF">MECONOPSIS ACULEATA</string>
    <string name="btnF">READ MORE</string>
    <string name="nameVF">Valley Of Flowers</string>
    <string name="nameDesVF">One of the Famous Tourist Spot\'s</string>
    <string name="nameDashBoardFRights">Dashboard | Flora</string>

    <!--  Fauna Dashboard  -->
    <string name="faunaIntro">As a result of deforestation, much of the original fauna of the Himalayas are restricted to protected areas and sanctuaries. Major fauna in the region are Himalayan Bear, Musk Deer, the wild Goat Ghoral, Bharal or Blue Goat, Wolves, Snow Leopards and varieties of deer such as Barking Deer. Avifauna in the region is regarded as one of the richest in the sub-continent, with over 500 species of birds.</string>
    <string name="nameMFa">Musk Deer</string>
    <string name="nameMoFa">Monal Bird</string>
    <string name="nameTFa">Tiger</string>
    <string name="nameEFa">Elephant</string>
    <string name="nameJFa">Jim Corbett National Park</string>
    <string name="nameDashBoardFaRights">Dashboard | Fauna</string>

    <!--  Musk Deer Activity  -->
    <string name="acMuskTitle">The Alpine Musk Deer</string>
    <string name="muskContent">The Alpine musk deer is the state animal of Uttarakhand. It is also known by Kasturi Mirg or Himalayan Musk Deer. This Alpine deer is found in coniferous and deciduous forests of Himalayan regions on the heights of 3000 to 5000 meters. Due to drastically hunting, it has become an endangered species. However, hunting of this deer is illegal. Scientific Name of The Alpine Musk Deer is Moschus chrysogaster.</string>

    <!--  Monal Bird Activity  -->
    <string name="acMonalTitle">Monal Bird</string>
    <string name="MonalContent">The Himalayan monal (Lophophorus impejanus), also known as the Impeyan monal and Impeyan pheasant, is a pheasant native to Himalayan forests and shrublands at elevations of 2,100–4,500 m (6,900–14,800 ft). It is part of the family Phasianidae and is listed as Least Concern on the IUCN Red List. It is the national bird of Nepal, where it is known as the danphe or danfe, and state bird of Uttarakhand, India, where it is known as monal. Himalayan Monal which features in the \'red\' category of International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) list, is facing a threat due to rampant degradation and disturbance of its habitat. In Uttarakhand, the birds are currently found in grassy slopes above the treeline, primarily in Chopta, Munsyari, Kedarnath Wildlife Sanctuary, Pindari and Dodital area of Uttarkashi.</string>

    <!--  Tiger Activity  -->
    <string name="acTigerTitle">Tiger</string>
    <string name="TigerContent">Uttarakhand is land to a number of Tigers in the country. Probably having the 2nd highest number of Tigers in Uttarakhand, there are some very popular Tiger Reserves in Uttarakhand. It is estimated that there is an approx number of 250 to 300 tigers in all the Tiger Reserves of Uttarakhand. Tiger population in Uttarakhand has risen from 227 to 340 since the last census, becoming the second State in the country after Karnataka with the highest number of tigers. “There has been an encouraging rise in tiger population in Uttarakhand. Currently Uttarakhand have 3 active Tiger reserves -: Corbett National Park, Kalagarh Tiger Reserve, Rajaji Tiger Reserve, and 2 more will be open soon named Nandhaur Wildlife Sanctuary and Surai range of Terai East.</string>

    <!--  Elephant Activity  -->
    <string name="acElephantTitle">Elephant</string>
    <string name="ElephantContent">Asian Elephant (Elephas maximus) is a threatened mammal species only second to its African cousin in size amongst all land mammals. Its status as per IUCN red list is endangered and it is placed in the appendix I of CITES. In Uttarakhand last direct count was conducted in the year 2007 which resulted in a count of 1346 elephants. Later in the year 2012, Asian nature conservation foundation, innovation centre at the Indian Institute of Sciences, Bangalore led by Dr R. Sukumar conducted elephant estimation in the state through dung decay method. This method was labour intensive involving high costs. Shiwalik Elephant reserve is the only Elephant reserve in the state of Uttarakhand.</string>

    <!--  Jim Corbett Activity  -->
    <string name="acJimCorbett">Jim Corbett National Park</string>
    <string name="JimCorbettContent">Jim Corbett National Park, which is a part of the larger Corbett Tiger Reserve, a Project Tiger Reserve lies in the Nainital district of Uttarakhand. The magical landscape of Corbett is well known and fabled for its tiger richness. Established in the year 1936 as Hailey National Park, Corbett has the glory of being India\'s oldest and most prestigious National Park. It is also being honored as the place where Project Tiger was first launched in 1973. This unique tiger territory is best known as the father who gave birth of the Project Tiger in India to protect the most endangered species and the Royal of India called Tigers. Spans over an extent of 520 square kilometers, its whole area comprises of hills, marshy depressions, riverine belts, grasslands and large lake. It is among the few tiger reserves in India that allows overnight stays in the lap of the National Park. Nature watch and wildlife viewing in the park is done in an open four wheeler Jeep and on elephant back. Sheltering a healthy population of tigers and rare species like Otters and the endemic fish eating crocodile, the national park is one of the most sought after destinations for the wildlife buffs. Dhikala, situated at the border of the extensive Patil Dun valley, is the most popular destination.</string>

    <!--  Brahma Kamal  -->
    <string name="BrahmaKamalContent">Brahma Kamal, also known as Saussurea Obvallata, belongs to the thistle tribe of flowering plants. Interestingly, this flower blooms only one night in a year, and that too, after sunset. It takes two hours or so for it to bloom fully to 8 inches in diameter. It is grown exclusively in Uttarakhand state in April-May and October. Brahma Kamal has been named after Brahma, the deity who created the universe. It is also called the King of Himalayan Flowers. It is also the state flower of Uttarakhand.</string>
    <string name="BMedicinalUse">The Brahma Kamalam flower has been used for centuries to treat several ailments. It is said to possess many medicinal properties. It improves memory, treats insomnia, increases concentration levels, strengthens immune system, enhances digestion, boosts metabolism used to treat constipation, cleanses blood, heals skin disorder, simulates hair growth, used to treat cough and cold, clears sinuses. The fragrance of Brahma Kamal is used in perfumery industries and in aromatherapy. It helps reduce stress, calms down nerves, and reduces anxiety.</string>
    <string name="BFacts">For the believers, they are an auspicious and wish-fulfilling nature. Brahma Kamal is offered in several holy shrines of Uttarakhand like Kedarnath, Badrinath and Tunganath. It blooms only in a few homes and is a harbinger of luck and prosperity in such places. It is believed that whoever prays to get any wish fulfilled while the flower is blooming will get the desire fulfilled. It is a local belief that Brahmakamal should be always gifted. It should not be sold or bought from anywhere.Some natives of Uttarakhand believe that Brahma Kamal protects its owner from evil eyes and bad influences. Others believe that this is the flower cherished by divine beings.</string>

    <!--  Burans  -->
    <string name="RContent">The onset of spring brings a beautiful cheer in Uttarakhand. And the cheer is justified with the refreshing weather at this time of the year and the blooming of the alluring rhododendrons. Burans (Buransh), which goes by the common name Rhododendron and scientific name Rhododendron Arboreum Sm. It is the State Tree of Uttarakhand and it is blooming is one of the most surreal wonders that you can witness in Uttarakhand.  Rhododendron has been derived from two Greek words Rhod meaning rosy red and dendron meaning tree. The name perfectly symbolizes the red flowers of the rhododendron trees. About Rhododendron Arboreum Burans or Rhododendron is an evergreen tree that grows up to the height of 20 m and has rough and pinkish-brown bark. The brightly colored flowers deep red to pink which bloom from late winter till early summer are the highlight of this tree. The months from January to March marks the blooming season of Burans in Uttarakhand.</string>
    <string name="RMedicinal">Medicinal Uses - As Burans has antioxidant, anti-inflammatory, and hepatoprotective properties, it is widely used in traditional medicines. Almost all the parts of Rhododendron are medicinal and used in a variety of ways to treat many ailments. Young leaves of Burans are applied to the forehead during headaches to treat it. The bark and flowers are used to treat digestive and respiratory ailments. Burans have excellent antioxidant, antiinflammatory, and antidiabetic properties making it not just appealing to the eye but potent for health too. Burans is considered good for heart, liver, diabetes, and is used for treating diarrhea. it is also considered good for the skin.</string>
    <string name="RFacts">Latest Findings about Rhododendron Flowers regarding Covid A group of biologists at Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Mandi has claimed to have stumbled upon a Himalayan flowering tree possessing antiviral properties with a potential to be used in the treatment against SARS-CoV2. Their study was published in the journal Biomolecular Structure and Dynamics. "The cells infected with SARS-Cov2 virus, when subjected to this specially prepared Buransh flower extract in a dose dependent manner, were kept under an incubation of 48 hours. It was found that the viral multiplication was affected. At a concentration of 1 mg/ml, nearly 80 per cent inhibition was achieved," said Masakapalli, Associate Professor of BioX Centre at IIT-Mandi. Date: 19 Jan 2022 </string>

    <!--  Pine  -->
    <string name="PineContent">A pine, locally known as Chir ka ped, (scientific name: Pinus roxburghii), is a conifer that covers about 16% of the forest area in Uttarakhand. It is one of the six pines in India that have maximum occurrence and area. Pine has been in the Himalayas for a long time, but the expansion of Indian Railways and resin-tapping during the colonial times gave it a big push. The number of pine trees plantations started increasing steadily by clearing the local forest vegetation. Both the Garhwal and the Kumaon Region of Uttarakhand have an abundance of pine trees. Being a pioneer species that love the sun, it is very easy for pine to grow in exposed sites where many other broad-leaved varieties do not exist. The root system of pine is shallow and it doesn’t require a lot of water. That is why the majority of the places with an abundance of pine forests have a high chance of becoming seriously drought-prone in summer months.</string>
    <string name="PineMedicinal">Ayurveda, the holistic science of herbal remedies has extensively mentioned this plant time and gain in several ayurvedic scriptures and journals for various indications which include, Kasahara (Relieves cough, Shwasha (relieves breathing difficulties),Balya (improves muscle strength), Kantya (relieves sore throat), Deepana (enhances stomach fire), Pachana (helps in digestion), Rochana (stimulates appetite), Anulomana (improves breathing), Vamana (prevents nausea and vomiting), Asra Dagdharuk (remedies wounds and burns), Vishaha (antitoxic), Sangrahini (treats diarrhoea), Kustha (treats skin disorders), Varnya (improves complexion), Rasayani (rejuvenates the whole body), Vayasthapana (prevents ageing), Jvara (useful in fever),   Amahara (treats indigestion), Dahahara (relieves burning sensation), Trutahara (relieves excessive thirst), Krimihara (relieves intestinal worms), Kanthya (improves voice), Arsha (treats piles), Krichra (treats painful micturition) and Pushtida (good for nutrition).</string>
    <string name="PineEffects">Forest Fires — The pine needles are highly inflammable and are the leading cause of forest fires in the region. Being fire-resistant, pine tree doesn’t burn in this fire and sheds leaves again next year, continuing this cycle every year. Lack of Water Retention — Because of the lack of bacteria, the water holding capacity of the soil decreases. Unlike areas which have a lot of oak trees, the region with the pine trees is mostly drought-prone and women have to walk sometimes 10 km to get the water for their normal use. No Bacterial Growth, thus Degraded Lands — Because of the pine presence, bacterias in the soil die and are replaced by a parasitic fungal relationship which only helps pine thrive and grow, and takes away resources available for other plants which could possibly grow. Biodiversity Loss — Due to the forest fires every year, a lot of animals and useful plant species which are not fire-resistant die leading to fauna and flora loss in the region. No Use for Livestock Pine needles are not used as a cattle feed, or bedding material for the livestock of the people, thus it is effectively of no use to the locals for their animal welfare.</string>

    <!--  Blue Poppy  -->
    <string name="BPContent">Blue Poppy the flowers are often referred to as QUEEN OF HIMALAYAN FLOWERS. This plants medicinal use in Uttrakhand is not so common in Tibetan, but is widely used. This is used in medicine to cure diseases associated with the head and is very well known in Tibetan medical methods. This flower has a pleasant and important place among the flowers of high altitude in the Himalayas.The sighting of these flowers is very common on the slope of Hemkunt Sahib during the monsoon season. Mostly the moraine part of the trek to Hemkund Sahib and Bhyundar khal, flowers valley to Badrinath trek remains completely filled with these tender blue flowers. Blue Poppys genus is MECONOPSIS Vig. World 40 species; 20 species of India. The term comes from the Greek word Mecon which means Poppy.</string>
    <string name="BPFacts">Blue Poppy is also known as MECONOPSIS ACULEATA, Aculeata means to wear a pickle, referring to the plant\'s prickly nature. Whole plant contains constituents of narcotics; roots are known to be toxic. The status is in doubt.</string>

    <!--  Valley Of Flowers  -->
    <string name="ValleyContent">With a stunning backdrop of the mighty Himalayan ranges, the Valley of Flowers National Park presents an ethereal view and an unforgettable experience for visitors. Spread over an area of 87 sq km in the Chamoli district, the Valley of Flowers National Park is a UNESCO World Heritage Site and forms one of the two core zones (the other being the Nanda Devi National Park) of the Nanda Devi Biosphere Reserve. The valley is believed to have been discovered in 1931, when three British mountaineers – led by Frank S Smythe – lost their way and chanced upon this spectacular valley. Attracted by the beauty of this place they named it the \'Valley of Flowers\'.</string>
    <string name="ValleyFacts">As the name suggests, Valley of Flowers is a destination where nature blooms in full glory offering a breathtaking experience. Exotic flowers (over 600 species) like orchids, poppies, primulas, marigold, daisies and anemones are an eye-catching spectacle. Sub-alpine forests birch and rhododendron cover parts of the park\'s area. The trek to the valley offers eye-catching spectacles like cascading waterfalls and wild streams.  Situated at an altitude of around 3,600 m above the sea level, the valley is also home to such rare and amazing wildlife species like the gray langur, the flying squirrel, the Himalayan weasel, and black bear, the red fox, the lime butterfly, the snow leopard and Himalayan monal, to name a few.</string>

</resources>


